Saurabh Kumar

Quality Assurance Lead

Navi Mumbai, India (+91)-9867244289

saurabhkumarblr09@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/saurabh-kumar-27650a112/

Having worked for more than 5 years of industry experience in software testing (Automation) with a solid understanding of test planning, test design, test execution and defect reporting. I am proficient in Java Selenium WebDriver, Appium and very well versed in programming languages like Java and Python. Proficient in Desktop and Mobile application testing.

Skills

Proficient:

JAVA

Python

Pytest

MySQL

Selenium WebDriver

Appium

POSTMAN and REST Assured

API testing

Agile Methodologies

Black Box testing

Functional Testing

Interoperability Testing

GUI testing

Integration Testing

OS:

Windows, Linux (Fedora, HP-UX, FreeBsd, Rhel), Mac

Tools:

Jira, Confluence, Selenium, webDriver, appium, TestNG, jenkins, Git

Education

Work Experience

QA Lead

Girnar Software Pvt. Ltd. (CarDekho), Bangalore

March 2022 – November 2022

- Apart from creating test scripts and for automation framework, I managed scrums, sprint boards, patch releases for the entire CarDekho platform.
- Used Java/python with selenium and Appium Webdriver to automate smoke suits of Used Car Retail of CarDekho.
- Proficient in using pytest to write and run automated smoke test cases.
- Conducted API testing for API built using REST assured libraries using POSTMAN for non UI featured functionalities
- Experience in handling kafka for lead checking and generation for UCR
- Lead the team using strategies like war room sessions across organization to capture bugs and construct roadmaps to successfully handle automation and manual tasks of UCR (Used Car Retail) platform.
- Built the team by handling new hires and handled performance metrics at every release.

QA Automation Engineer

Flipkart India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

Nov 2019 – Mar 2022

 Designed the entire automation framework for SHOPSY, FK REFURB from ground up. Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Technological University, Mumbai

June 2013 - May 2017

D.A.V Public School,

Mumbai - HSC.

June 2012 - May 2013

Achieved 70% with Math and science as core subjects

D.A.V Public School,

Mumbai - SSC.

June 2011 - May 2012

Achieved 90%

Awards and Recognition

Received master of ceremony award at national level in NIC camp

Successfully completed C-cert in National Cadet Corps

- Used Java/python with selenium and Appium Webdriver to automate smoke suits of Used Car Retail of CarDekho.
- Proficient in using pytest to write and run automated smoke test cases.
- Conducted API testing for API built using REST assured libraries using POSTMAN for non UI featured functionalities
- Devised test suites, E2E tests, API testing to find vulnerabilities and memory leak testing to optimize experience for mass traffic.
- Collaborated with designers to compare design metrics using Zeplin and Figma.
- Lead the entire deployment and release cycle to deliver on time deployment.
- Maintained release notes for all the production releases.
 Successfully tested and deployed 'SHOPSY' and FK-REFURB a social commerce platform for live traffic

QA Assurance Engineer Flexera Software LLP, Bangalore

Jul 2017 - Aug 2019

- Used scripts for UI automation using selenium WebDriver, devised
 Perl scripts for testing and penetration testing tools like Wireshark
 and Burp tool on products to track failure analysis.
- Collaborated with developers to enhance performance and tracking regression bottlenecks.
- Analyzed failed test cases, recorded results and generated reports.